

# **Serdar CAGLAR**

## **Data Scientist**

■ serdarildercaglar@gmail.com

+905424999344

Istanbul, Turkey

### in linkedin.com/in/serdarildercaglar

github.com/serdarildercaglar

k kaggle.com/serdarcaglar

## GENERAL SKILLS

Data Analysis | Machine Learning

Deep Learning | NLP

Statistical Analysis | Pattern Recognition

**Data Visualization** 

**Database Structures & Algorithms** 

**Data Preparation** 

**Agile Methodologies** (Scrum, Kanban)

## I TECHNICAL SKILLS



### **EDUCATION**

**Data Science Trainee,** *Clarusway IT School* 03/2021 – 12/2021

Bachelor's of Arts / Teacher, Gaziosmanpasa University 09/2004 – 05/2008 | Tokat, Turkey 3.7 / 4

### **PROFILE**

1+ years of experience in Data Analysis, Data Manipulation, Data Visualization, Machine Learning Modelling and Business Intelligence. A general background in NLP and Deep Learning, along with their corresponding tools and techniques. Performed data extraction, analysis and modelling with Python libraries like NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn and Scikit-Learn. Experience with SQL, Google Spreadsheet and Tableau for data manipulation and visualization. Able to translating results into understandable terms for the success of the organization and business decisions. Strong analytical, creative thinking, problem-solving, and technical skills.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Data Analyst Mentor,** Clarusway

05/2021 - present | USA

- Trained Tableau, led and reviewed Tableau projects.
- Provided technical guidance and mentoring to students to and assist with projects and assignments.
- Contributed in weekly live group mentoring sessions with industry-experienced data scientists and completed indepth capstone projects.
- Mastered skills in SQL, Python, Tableau, Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, Data Analysis, Hypothesis Testing.
- Collected and cleaned large datasets with Python by utilizing SQL and MS SQL Server.
- Extracted, processed and analyzed complex datasets using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.

**Teacher,** *Ministry of National Education* 09/2010 – 07/2016 | Turkey

## **CERTIFICATES**

**Data Analytics** *⊘* (Clarusway) | **Spark NLP** *⊘* 

**Spark NLP Healthcare** *⊘* 

## PROJECTS

### AutoScout24 Car price prediction EDA,

Pandas, Matplotlib, SciPy, Seaborn, Numpy

This project contains real data from AutoScout24.de. The data here was going to be inserted into a Machine Learning model that will make a price estimation based on the given features of the cars. I was asked to clean this data to be inserted into the ML model accordingly and identify columns and features that will

not affect the price and get rid of them.

### **Exploratory Data Analysis on traffic stops in Rhode**

Island, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Numpy

I worked on real data taken from a certain region in America. I made many analyzes on the reason why the police stopped people, the gender of the driver, the race, the time and date they stopped. Gained a better understanding of the resulting analysis with data visualizations.

**E-Commerce Data and Customer Retention Analysis with SQL,** *Microsoft SQL Server* 

Global Covid-19 Tracker Data Visualization, Tableau

Data Visualization on Bike Demand,

Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib



### **LANGUAGES**

Turkish (Native)

**English** (Upper Intermediate)

## (F)

### **INTERESTS**

- Swimming
- Blockchain
- Tech
- Artificial Intelligence
- Cyber Security